New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Photograph Collection
© 2004 University of Connecticut
New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Photograph Collection.
undated, 1900-1971.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad.
1.5 linear feet.
MSS19910132
Photographs of railroad equipment, stations, and crossings, and of the effects of the Floods of 1955 in Connecticut.
History
For almost one hundred years the New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad, better known as the New Haven Railroad, was the primary means of passenger and freight transportation in southern New England. Chartered in 1872, this merger between the New York & New Haven and Hartford & New Haven railroads later included the long desired rail link between Boston and New York. Approximately one hundred small independent railroads were built in southern New England between 1826 and the 1880s. By 1904, the majority were absorbed into the vast New Haven system. At its peak in 1929, the New Haven Railroad owned and operated 2,131 miles of track throughout eastern New York, Connecticut, Massachusetts, and Rhode Island.
The local railroad lines that eventually became part of the New Haven system developed in response to local business and transportation needs. Unlike the Western states, where railroads preceded and shaped settlement, in the Northeast they served primarily to link existing towns, businesses, and markets. The New Haven system thus developed as a result of numerous consolidations and mergers. The New Haven traced its founding to 1826, when one of its predecessor companies originated, but the New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad was not chartered until 1872. The company followed the pattern of consolidation established by the Pennsylvania Railroad and other companies, particularly after 1889, when major lines in Connecticut, Rhode Island, and southern Massachusetts provided a strong network linking New York and Boston. By 1890, company revenue exceeded $100,000,000 per year, and the New Haven employed 4,000 people to serve twelve million passengers annually.
This success led a wealthy group of New York investors, headed by J. P. Morgan, to seek and gain control of the New Haven's board. In 1903, Morgan installed Charles Mellen as president of the railroad. Together Morgan and Mellen set out to achieve a complete monopoly of transportation in New England. Substantial improvements to the system were made during the Mellen years, including electrification of rail lines between Woodlawn, New York, and New Haven, Connecticut, and construction of a power generating plant in Cos Cob, Connecticut. These accomplishments, however, were overshadowed by Morgan's ambitious schemes to dominate all modes of transportation in New England. Steamboat lines, trolley companies, and other railroad lines were purchased regardless of price and incorporated into the New Haven system.
An investigation of the New Haven's activities by Louis Brandeis in 1907 revealed the overextended railroad was on the verge of financial collapse. Morgan's death in 1913 and Mellen's subsequent resignation brought to a close a stormy period in the New Haven's history.
During the First World War, all of the railroads in the United States, including the New Haven Railroad, were operated by the federal government. After the war, under Edward Pearson, President through 1928, the railroad was able to recover partially, despite increasing competition from automobiles, by sharing in the national economic growth of the 1920s. The company tried to meet this transportation competition by forming the New England Transportation Company, which operated a fleet of trucks and buses. Recovery of the New Haven, however, was cut short by the Depression of the 1930s, and in 1935 the New Haven plunged into bankruptcy. The company remained in trusteeship until 1947, when it returned to private ownership.
A series of struggles for control of the company in the post World War II period severely weakened the management of the company and its ability to adapt to changes in the transportation industry. The completion of the Connecticut Turnpike and other superhighways and the start of air shuttle service between Boston and New York intensified competition. The company's historic liability as a railroad overburdened with many short, costly branch lines further accelerated its decline.
On 7 July 1961, the New Haven Railroad once again went into receivership. A seven year trusteeship period followed, culminating in the absorption of the New Haven in the Penn Central system on 1 January 1969. Three years later the Penn Central itself collapsed into bankruptcy. The former components of the New Haven Railroad were divided among several entities. Freight service was assumed by Conrail when it was formed in 1976, although the Providence & Worcester also provided freight service on portions of the former New Haven, as did a few other operators. Passenger commuter service was funded by the New York Metropolitan Transit Authority and the Connecticut Department of Transportation. Long-haul passenger service was provided by Amtrak beginning in 1971. After 1976 passenger commuter service was operated by Conrail. In 1982, the United States Congress passed legislation that forced Conrail to divest itself of its commuter rail lines. On 1 January 1983, Metro-North Commuter Railroad, under joint ownership of the states of New York and Connecticut, took over all commuter passenger service. Amtrak continued to handle all long-haul passenger service.
The history of the New Haven Railroad reveals a company formed by one of the classic merger and consolidation patterns of the late 19th century, which was later unable to respond effectively to major changes in the transportation industry. The company's rapid growth, collapse, temporary recovery, and final dissolution offer a dramatic story, with government regulation, internal management decisions, and market competition playing important roles in the company's history.
Scope and Content
These photographs were a part of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad records; they were separated from the main collection in order to improve access to the photographs. Additional photographs still exist in the main collection.
Arrangement
Series I: Railroad Equipment ( 1944-1971 ) contains photographs of box cars, engines, flat cars, passenger cars and track repair machines. Most of the photographs depict NHRR equipment, although some of the photographs are of other railroads.
Series II: Railroad stations ( undated, 1900-1968 ) contains interior and exterior shots of New Haven Railroad stations in New York, Connecticut, Massachusetts and Rhode Island. The photographs are organized by state and then by station.
Series III: Railroad Crossings and other Property ( 1916, 1944-1968 ) contains photographs of railroad crossings, yards, bridges, tracks and other property located in New York, Connecticut, Massachusetts and Rhode Island. This series is organized chronologically by the date of the photograph.
Series IV: 1955 Flood ( 1955 ) is a series of photographs, primarily aerial, which document extensive flood damage to New Haven Railroad property in western Connecticut. The back of each photograph was numbered by the NHRR. This series is organized numerically by the assigned number.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to New England railroads. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Company.
Subjects:
Railroads--New England.; Floods--Connecticut--1955.; Railroad stations--New England.
Document Types:
Photographs.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Detailed Description
- Series I: Railroad Equipment, 1944-1971
  - Milwaukee Boxcar, 1944 May (Box 1)
  - Box cars (various), 1944 June (Box 1)
  - Box cars (various), 1944 July (Box 1)
  - Railroad Express Agency Boxcar, 1944 December (Box 1)
  - Box cars (various), 1945 March (Box 1)
  - Erie Railroad Boxcar, 1945 May (Box 1)
  - Car Compressors, 1945 September (Box 1)
  - Box cars (various), 1945 October (Box 1)
  - Plumbers Shanty, New Haven, Connecticut, 1945 October (Box 1)
  - New England Transportation Bus, 1945 December (Box 1)
  - Railroad Crane, Adzing and Grinding machines, 1946 January (Box 1)
  - Boxcars and Freight handling equipment, 1946 October (Box 1)
  - Railroad cars (various), 1947 February (Box 1)
  - New Haven Locomotive 1500, 1947 February (Box 1)
  - Norfolk & Western Railroad Car 47997, 1947 May (Box 1)
  - Railroad cars (various), 1948 March (Box 1)
  - Lackawanna Railroad car, 1948 April (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger cars, 1948 April (Box 1)
  - Coal Hopper Bridge, 1948 September (Box 1)
  - Switching Engine, 1948 November (Box 1)
  - Baggage Truck, 1948 December (Box 1)
  - Tire Setting machine, 1949 April (Box 1)
  - Fruit Growers Express Reefer car 56213, 1950 May (Box 1)
  - Railroad cars and tankers (various), 1950 July (Box 1)
  - New Haven Diesel Locomotive 0402, 1950 July (Box 1)
  - Matisa Tile Tamping machine, 1950 December (Box 1)
  - New York Central Railroad car 169483, 1952 June (Box 1)
  - Fruit Growers Express Railroad car 80975, 1952 June (Box 1)
  - Cambria & Indiana Freight car 388, 1952 August (Box 1)
  - Railroad cars (various), 1953 January (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 8695, 1953 June (Box 1)
  - Railroad Crossover switch, 1953 July (Box 1)
  - Locomotives (various), 1953 August (Box 1)
  - Anchor Bridge, 1953 August (Box 1)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad car 10340, 1953 September (Box 1)
  - New Haven Railroad Engine 792, 1953 September (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 4464, 1954 November (Box 1)
  - B & M Storage car, 1955 January (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 309, 1955 May (Box 1)
  - Nickel Plate Road Boxcar 86299, 1956 September (Box 1)
  - C. B. & Q Boxcar 18417, 1956 December (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car (interior), 1957 June (Box 1)
  - Derailment, Jewett City, Connecticut, 1957 July (Box 1)
  - Rail Saw, 1957 August (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 8290, 1958 March (Box 1)
  - New York Central Boxcar 41624, 1958 April (Box 1)
  - New Haven Diesel Locomotive 2009, 1958 November (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 4414, 1958 November (Box 1)
  - Reading Railroad car 31249, 1958 November (Box 1)
  - MDT Reefer car 9002, 1959 March (Box 1)
  - New Haven Baggage car (interior), 1959 May (Box 1)
  - New Haven Railroad cars with locomotive, 1960 January (Box 1)
  - New Haven Locomotive 0409, 1960 March (Box 1)
  - Track Jack, 1960 June (Box 1)
  - New Haven Freight car 80493, 1960 November (Box 1)
  - Jordan Spreader (track flanger), 1961 January (Box 1)
  - New Haven Locomotive 2018, 1961 November (Box 1)
  - Signal Station, Putnam, Connecticut, 1961 November (Box 1)
  - New Haven Locomotive 2003, 1962 May (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 4449, 1962 September (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 8338, 1962 December (Box 1)
  - Crane car, 1962 December (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger cars 4419, 4408, 1963 January (Box 1)
  - Bethel Train collision, 1963 August (Box 1)
  - New Haven Caboose C-569, 1964 January (Box 1)
  - Santa Fe Railroad Boxcar 20014, 1964 February (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 42, 1964 March (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 8688, 1964 May (Box 1)
  - Tie Master machine, 1964 May (Box 1)
  - Motorized Clark Cat, 1964 August (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 0401, 1964 October (Box 1)
  - C. B. & Q Boxcar 9435, 1964 December (Box 1)
  - New Haven Passenger car 8654, 1964 December (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 2557, 1965 February (Box 1)
  - Power Jack, 1965 March (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 0975, 1965 October (Box 1)
  - Missouri Pacific Railroad car 20695, 1965 October (Box 1)
  - Rail Compressor and Spike Driver, 1965 November (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 1604, 1966 January (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 0960, 1966 January (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvania Railroad car 371619, 1966 July (Box 1)
  - Electric Baggage Truck, 1966 July (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 1217, 1966 August (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 542, 1966 September (Box 1)
  - Railroad Turntable, Cedar Hill, Connecticut, 1966 September (Box 1)
  - Milwaukee Railroad Flatcar, 1966 November (Box 1)
  - Breaker Yard, 1966 November (Box 1)
  - New Haven Caboose 595, 1967 March (Box 1)
  - Santa Fe Boxcar 22252, 1967 April (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engines 1610, 1409, 1609, 1967 May (Box 1)
  - North American Railroad Tanker 21270, 1967 May (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 546, 1967 May (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine Switcher 646, 1967 August (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 545, 1967 September (Box 1)
  - Tire Tamper, 1967 October (Box 1)
  - Railroad Tanker cars, 1968 March (Box 1)
  - New Haven Engine 2009, 1968 July (Box 1)
  - New Haven Budd car 47, 1968 August (Box 1)
  - New Haven Budd car 48, 1968 August (Box 1)
  - Buck Unloader (automobile unloader), 1971 July (Box 1)
- Series II: Railroad Stations, undated, 1900-1968
  - Connecticut (Box 2)
    - Berlin
      - 1964 March
      - 1968 October
    - Bridgeport
      - 1944 December
      - 1952 August
      - 1961 May
      - 1963 March
      - 1966 July
      - 1968 July
      - 1969 June
    - Cos Cob
      - 1958 November
    - Danbury
      - 1949 December
    - Fairfield
      - 1962 May
    - Greens Farms
      - 1965 June
    - Hartford
      - 1955 February
      - 1964 May
      - 1966 August
    - Hartford (Morgan Street Railroad Yard)
      - 1944 August
    - Meriden
      - 1945 December
      - 1959 July
      - 1962 October
      - 1964 July
    - Naugatuck
      - 1952 February
    - New Canaan (waiting room)
      - 1956 October
    - New Haven
      - 1951 March - June
      - 1951 January
      - 1961 March
      - 1967 June
      - 1968 May
    - New London
      - 1946 September
      - 1956 December
      - 1963 July
    - Norwich
      - 1962 August
    - Old Greenwich
      - 1963 January
    - Plainville
      - 1952 February
    - Riverside
      - 1954 August
      - 1961 August
    - South Norwalk
      - 1946 September
      - 1961 November
      - 1966 September
    - Stamford
      - 1945 November
      - 1958 March
      - 1960 August
    - Torrington
      - 1948 March
    - Wallingford
      - 1950 March
    - Waterbury
      - 1954 January
    - Westport
      - 1949 June
      - 1952 June
      - 1959 September
      - 1961 March
    - Willimantic
      - 1945 August
  - Massachusetts (Box 2)
    - Back Bay, Boston
      - 1960 November
    - Bridgewater
      - 1965 January
    - Buzzard's Bay
      - undated
    - Chatham
      - undated
    - Mansfield
      - 1965 April
    - North Station, Boston
      - 1965 March
      - 1967 July
    - Norwood (Winslows)
      - circa 1900
    - Sharon
      - undated, 1936
    - South Station, Boston
      - 1965 November
    - West Roxbury
      - 1932, 1948
  - New York (Box 2)
    - 125th Street Station, New York City
      - 1958 April
      - 1966 December
    - Portchester
      - 1946 January
  - Rhode Island (Box 2)
    - Providence, 1968 September
- Series III: Railroad Crossings and other Property, 1916-1968
  - Harlem River, New York City, 1944 March (Box 3)
  - Railroad Yard, Cranston, RI, 1944 March (Box 3)
  - Railroad Bridge, Windsor, CT, 1944 April (Box 3)
  - Hamilton Street Railraod Crossing, Hartford, CT, 1944 June (Box 3)
  - Railroad Yard, Norwich, CT, 1944 July (Box 3)
  - Railroad Yard, Hartford, CT, 1944 August (Box 3)
  - Railroad Tracks, West Mystic, CT, 1944 October (Box 3)
  - Park Street Crossing, New Britain, CT, 1944 October (Box 3)
  - Freight House, Bridgeport, CT, 1944 November (Box 3)
  - Railroad Station Crossing, Granby, CT, 1945 February (Box 3)
  - Dewitt Street Bridge, New Haven, CT, 1945 February (Box 3)
  - Dalton Road Railroad Crossing, Falls Village, CT, 1945 April (Box 3)
  - Belle Dock Yard, New Haven, CT, 1945 December (Box 3)
  - Glenbrook Road Railroad Crossing, Glenbrook, CT, 1946 February (Box 3)
  - Railroad Bridge, Westfield, MA, 1946 April (Box 3)
  - Catenary Bridge, Bridgeport, CT, 1946 November (Box 3)
  - Parker Street Railroad Crossing, South Windsor, CT, 1947 March (Box 3)
  - Sullivan Street Railroad Crossing, South Windsor, CT, 1947 March (Box 3)
  - Cherry Street Railroad Crossing, Meriden, CT, 1947 March (Box 3)
  - Gas House Private Crossing, Norwich, CT, 1947 August (Box 3)
  - School Street Railroad Crossing, Central Village, CT, 1948 February (Box 3)
  - Bay Ridge Yard, Brooklyn, NY, 1948 February (Box 3)
  - Brook Street Private Crossing, Shelton, CT, 1948 March (Box 3)
  - Forbes Avenue, New Haven, CT, 1948 November (Box 3)
  - Morgan Street Railroad Yard, Hartford, CT, 1948 November (Box 3)
  - Railroad Tracks, New Haven, CT, 1948 December (Box 3)
  - Campbells Crossing, Vernon Center, CT, 1949 January (Box 3)
  - Main Street Railroad Crossing, Cromwell, CT, 1949 March (Box 3)
  - Railroad Yard, Bridgeport, CT, 1949 May (Box 3)
  - Greenwood Avenue Railroad Crossing, Bethel, CT, 1949 August (Box 3)
  - White Street Railroad Crossing, Danbury, CT, 1949 December (Box 3)
  - Railroad Street Passway, Wallingford, CT, 1950 March (Box 3)
  - Franklin Street Bridge, New Haven, CT, 1950 June (Box 3)
  - Union Street Railroad Crossing, Willimantic, CT, 1951 August (Box 3)
  - Water Street Railroad Yard, New Haven, CT, 1952 June (Box 3)
  - Beach Street Railroad Crossing, Plainville, CT, 1952 June (Box 3)
  - Hartford Street Railroad Crossing, Wallingford, CT, 1953 September (Box 3)
  - Lamberton Street Bridge, New Haven, CT, 1953 October (Box 3)
  - Hoyt Street Railroad Crossing, Springdale, CT, 1953 November (Box 3)
  - Greenwood Avenue Railroad Crossing, Bethel, CT, 1954 October (Box 3)
  - Greenwood Avenue, Stamford, CT, 1954 November (Box 3)
  - Connecticut River Drawbridge, Lyme, CT, 1954 December (Box 3)
  - Main Street Railroad Crossing, Niantic, CT, 1955 January (Box 3)
  - Coast Guard Base, New London, CT, 1955 March (Box 3)
  - Railroad Yards, Hartford, CT, 1956 August (Box 3)
  - Water Street Railroad Yard, New Haven, CT, 1956 December (Box 3)
  - Broad Street Railroad Crossing, Fairville, CT, 1957 December (Box 3)
  - Howard Avenue Railroad Bridge, New Haven, CT, 1959 December (Box 3)
  - Water Street Bridge, New Haven, CT, 1960 March (Box 3)
  - Main Street Railroad Crossing, New Britain, CT, 1960 July (Box 3)
  - Bridge Street Railroad Crossing, Windsor Locks, CT, 1960 July (Box 3)
  - Forbes Street Railroad Tracks, New Haven, CT, 1960 November (Box 3)
  - Private Railroad Crossing, Kent, CT, 1961 January (Box 3)
  - Eighth Street Railroad Crossing, Norwich, CT, 1961 March (Box 3)
  - Railroad Crossing, Central Village, CT, 1961 April (Box 3)
  - Railroad Crossing, Windsor Locks, CT, 1961 April (Box 3)
  - Passenger Walk Bridge, Seymour, CT, 1961 April (Box 3)
  - Crescent Street Railroad Crossing, Glenbrook, CT, 1961 June (Box 3)
  - Bridge Street Railroad Crossing, New Milford, CT, 1961 October (Box 3)
  - Route 101 Railroad Crossing, Dayville, CT, 1962 April (Box 3)
  - Runaround, New Haven, CT, 1962 October (Box 3)
  - Railroad Tracks, Hartford, CT, 1962 November (Box 3)
  - Ellis Street Railroad Tracks, New Britain, CT, 1962 December (Box 3)
  - Maple Avenue Railroad Crossing, Danbury, CT, 1963 January (Box 3)
  - Commercial Street Railroad Crossing, New Britain, CT, 1963 January (Box 3)
  - Railroad Bridge, Westerly, RI, 1963 February (Box 3)
  - Brook Street Railroad Crossing, Meriden, CT, 1963 March (Box 3)
  - NHRR Headquarters, New Haven, CT, 1963 May (Box 3)
  - State Street Crossing, New London, CT, 1963 July (Box 3)
  - Washington Street Bridge, Dorchester, MA, 1963 September (Box 3)
  - Franklin Street Crossing, Danielson, CT, 1964 August (Box 3)
  - Clinton Street Railroad Bridge, Fall River, MA, 1965 February (Box 3)
  - Main Street Railroad Crossing, Danbury, CT, 1965 February (Box 3)
  - Main Street Railroad Crossing, New Britain, CT, 1965 April (Box 3)
  - Army Base, Boston, MA, 1965 June (Box 3)
  - Boston Switch, Central Falls, RI, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Westminster Street Bridge, Providence, RI, 1966 March (Box 3)
  - Railroad Bridge, South Norwalk, CT, 1966 March (Box 3)
  - Hamlet Avenue Crossing, Woonsocket, RI, 1966 April (Box 3)
  - Freight Temrinal, Boston, MA, 1966 May (Box 3)
  - Thames River Railroad Bridge, Groton, CT, 1966 May (Box 3)
  - Mystic River Railroad Bridge, Mystic, CT, 1966 May (Box 3)
  - Main Street Railroad Crossing, Webster, MA, 1966 July (Box 3)
  - Wall Street Railroad Bridge, New Haven, CT, 1966 December (Box 3)
  - Goodrich Street Railroad Crossing, Hamden, CT, 1967 March (Box 3)
  - Bassett Street Railroad Crossing, New Haven, CT, 1967 May (Box 3)
  - Hamilton Street Railroad Crossing, Hartford, CT, 1967 May (Box 3)
  - Main Street Railroad Crossing, Danielson, CT, 1967 June (Box 3)
  - Hall Avenue Railroad Crossing, Wallingford, CT, 1967 July (Box 3)
  - West Street Bridge, New Haven, CT, 1967 July (Box 3)
  - U.S. Submarine Base Crossing, Groton, CT, 1967 December (Box 3)
  - Hunts Point Market, Bronx NY, 1968 February (Box 3)
  - Chapel and James Street Railroad Crossing, New Haven, CT, 1968 May (Box 3)
  - Railroad Yard, Framingham, MA, 1968 July (Box 3)
  - Forbes Avenue Railroad Tracks, New Haven, CT, 1968 November (Box 3)
  - Colony Street Railroad Crossing, Meriden, CT, 1968 December (Box 3)
- Series IV: 1955 Flood
  [The numbers in this series refer to Box: photograph (as assigned by the NHRR)].
  - Naugatuck Valley north of Ansonia (Box 4:, Other 1)
  - Collinsville (Box 4:, Other 2)
  - Ansonia (Box 4:, Other 3)
  - North of Ansonia (Box 4:, Other 4)
  - Between Beacon Falls and Naugatuck (Box 4:, Other 5)
  - North of Plainville (Box 4:, Other 6)
  - Jericho on Winsted Line (Box 4:, Other 7-8)
  - Ansonia (Box 4:, Other 9)
  - North of Ansonia (Box 4:, Other 10)
  - Between Union City - Waterbury (Box 4:, Other 11)
  - Collinsville (Box 4:, Other 12)
  - Ansonia (Box 4:, Other 13)
  - Turkey Brook (Box 4:, Other 14)
  - Derby Junction (Box 4:, Other 15)
  - Unidentified (Box 4:, Other 16)
  - Unionville (Box 4:, Other 17)
  - Winsted Line (Box 4:, Other 18)
  - Turkey Brook (Box 4:, Other 19)
  - North of Plainville (Box 4:, Other 20)
  - Winsted Line (Box 4:, Other 21)
  - Farmington (Box 4:, Other 22)
  - Cornwall Bridge (Box 4:, Other 23)
  - Bank Street Junction, Waterbury (Box 4:, Other 24)
  - Winsted Line (Box 4:, Other 25)
  - Waterville, Chase Plant (Box 4:, Other 26)
  - Famington River, New Hartford Branch (Box 4:, Other 27)
  - Forestville (Box 4:, Other 28)
  - Plainville (Box 4:, Other 29)
  - Waterville (Box 4:, Other 30)
  - Farmington (Box 4:, Other 31)
  - Waterbury (Box 4:, Other 32)
  - North of Thomaston (Box 4:, Other 33)
  - Waterville (Box 4:, Other 34)
  - West Cornwall (Box 4:, Other 35)
  - Unidentified (Box 4:, Other 36)
  - Thomaston (Box 4:, Other 37)
  - Waterville (Box 4:, Other 38)
  - Housatonic River at New Milford (Box 4:, Other 39)
  - West of Plainville (Box 4:, Other 40)
  - Forestville (Box 4:, Other 41)
  - Granby (Box 4:, Other 42)
  - Farmington (Box 4:, Other 43)
  - North of Cornwall Bridge (Box 4:, Other 44)
  - Junction with Watertown Branch (Box 4:, Other 45)
  - North of Corwall Bridge (Box 4:, Other 46)
  - Waterville (Box 4:, Other 47)
  - West of Terryville (Box 4:, Other 48)
  - West of Terryville (Box 4:, Other 49)
  - Bank Street, Waterbury (Box 4:, Other 50)
  - Waterville (Box 4:, Other 51)
  - Near Avon (Box 4:, Other 52)
  - North of Plainville (Box 4:, Other 53)
  - Farmington (Box 4:, Other 54)
  - West Cornwall (Box 4:, Other 55)
  - Corwall Bridge (Box 4:, Other 56)